<Document>
# Getting Started

## Welcome to Parkstation!
You and your crewmates have started your shift aboard a Nanotraasen space station.
Each of you has a job to do, hopefully enjoying yourselves while doing so.

You are all a crew of people who work together (even the Clown).
You should not be harming each other unless you have an extremely good reason.
Before resorting to violence, call Security over the radio, attempt to stun and detain your assailants.
Do not commit murder unless it's your job to (you are an [color=#FF0000]antagonist[/color]).

Please make sure you understand the Server Rules, which you can see at any time through the escape menu.

If you have any questions:
- Look through the guidebooks
- Ask your colleagues in character, over radio, or in person
- Ask Administrators via ahelp (F1) or Discord


## Gameplay
SS14 is a role playing game at its core -- you play as a member of the station crew, which you can customize from the lobby prior to joining the game.
From there, you can select the jobs your character preforms, what they look like, how people are expected to refer to them, etc.

As soon as you arrive you're expected to act as your character, or 'in character' (IC).
When you're in character you forget any knowledge of previous rounds or the world outside, and play as if you're actually a member of the crew.

'Out of Character' (OOC) is the opposite of IC.
This includes any conversations you have outside of the game world, e.g., in the designated OOC chat, in a private message, or a chat with friends.
You shouldn't discuss the current round or anything that's IC in OOC channels (ick ock).
Likewise anything you see or read in OOC MUST NOT be used by your character in game.
If one of your friends identifies a traitor, or tells you they're dying in a certain location, you MUST ignore it.
Going to help them is known as metagaming or metacomming, and will get you banned.

If you suspect a player in game is metagaming -
(for example, if you're a traitor and someone kills you before you've done anything to them) -
you should report them via ahelp or the Discord.

To summarize, when you're in game:

[color=#FF0000]DO:[/color]
- Keep in character
- Act like your character would in the given situation
- Ask for help if you need it.

[color=#FF0000]DON'T:[/color]
- Discuss the round elswhere (until the round is over)
- Share information about the round OOC


## Antagonists

To give the game a bit of excitement, some players are selected to work against the crew in some way by acting as an Antagonist, or Antag.
There are various types of antags, like Traitors, Wizards, Nuclear Operatives, etc
You can volunteer to play as an antag through the character editor if you are whitelisted.

Even if you volunteered to be an antag, it is not likely that you will be picked.
When a round starts, players will be automatically and randomly selected to fill the antagonist roles.
The game will notify them of their assignment in chat.
If you're not sure you've been selected, press [color=#a4885c]C[/color].
If you're an antag, you'll have a list of objectives.
If not, you're a normal employee.

[color=#FF0000]Being an antagonist is not an excuse to go on a murder spree (murderboning).[/color]
Your job is to complete your objectives in a fun way for everyone.
On occasion, that will include the assassination of a target.
Sometimes it will include escaping alive or dying a glorious death.
How you complete these objectives is up to you, but keep in mind that there are other syndicate agents on the station that have their own objectives.
While your objectives take priority and might not always align with theirs, you generally shouldn't recklessly endanger their missions by destroying the station or blindly murdering.
If you manage to identify them, working with them can be very mutually beneficial.

As always, try to have fun with your role!
Ideally not at everyone's expense... but that's up to you (and the Administrators).

## Responding to Antagonists

If you suspect someone is an antagonist, report them to Security as fast as possible, and do what you can to protect yourself.
Remember, antagonists are legally people too, so they must be arrested and prosecuted if at all possible.

## Self-Antagonizing

Self-Antagonizing (self-antag) is when you are NOT an antagonist, yet you go out of your way to break the law, damage the station, or murder.
Breaking the law is not inherently self-antagonizing, but attacking your crewmates, attempting to break into high security areas, and hoarding items you don't need ARE.
[color=#FF0000]Self-Antagonizing can and will get you banned.[/color]


## RDM

Random DeathMatch (RDM) is the act of attempting to kill someone for no reason.
If you are being attacked, the other person is likely an Antagonist.
[color=#008000]If you are unsure, ask the admins.[/color]
The admins shouldn't tell you exactly if they are an antagonist, but will say if they should or should not be RDMing and will take needed actions.
</Document>
