<Document>
# The Important Stuff

## Welcome to Parkstation!

Welcome to Parkstation!
The round starts as you and your crewmates begin your shift, employed aboard a Nanotrasen-branded space vessel.
Each crewman aboard the vessel has a job to do, on top of living out the daily routine of a full-time Nanotrasen employee at whatever level you may be at. Guides and IC information for each role will be provided later.

All crew are fellow employees, a large number of whom may be used to working with each other, Clown included.
Above all else, the crew are human (more or less) and should be attempting to get along with each other as best as possible.
Before resorting to violence, call Security over the radio, attempt to knock down, or even detain your assailants.
Do not commit murder lightly, do not act as a sociopath for the sake of it, and do not push rules or play merely for reactions.
Try to play with the united goal of roleplay, and a good time.

Please make sure you understand the Server Rules, which you can see at any time through the escape menu, and ensure you are here for the right reasons.
If you're ever unsure or confused while playing, do not hesitate to:

- Look through the documentation- the fact that you're reading this is a great sign!
- Ask your colleagues in character, over the radio, or in person, as long as the confusion makes sense in the world.
- Ask your fellow players out of character, either in [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] or [color=#66e0e0]LOOC[/color].
- Or of course, ask Administrators via [color=#DC143C]AHelp[/color] (F1) or Discord.


## Meta; For The Newbies

Space Station 14 is a role-playing game at its core- and Parkstation intends to let that fact truly shine. You play as a member of the station crew, which you can customize from the lobby prior to joining the game.
From there, you can select the jobs your character performs, what they look like, how people are expected to refer to them, etc.

As soon as you arrive you're expected to act as your character, or 'in character' (IC). Try to make sure your character isn't detracting from the experience of others, keep in mind that being 'the quiet one' isn't necessarily a bad thing,
as long as you don't outright refuse to interact.
When you're in character you forget any knowledge of previous rounds or the world outside, and play as if you're actually a member of the crew.

'Out of Character' ([color=#66bbff]OOC[/color]) is the opposite of IC.
This includes any conversations you have outside of the game world, as well as 'meta' knowledge about the world your character wouldn't know or consider.
To discuss [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] topics in the game, look to your chat window, which will either be a box in the top right of your screen or taking up the entire right side of your screen based on your UI selection.
Clicking the '[color=#bbbbbb]Local[/color]' label until it reads [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] or [color=#66e0e0]LOOC[/color] will allow you to speak either globally to all players or locally to the players around you, with the name of your character, respectively.
There are plenty of reasons you might want to do this. Some good examples for [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] would be at the end of a round, to discuss the events of that round post-game, or to request information about the game you might need.
Good reasons to use [color=#66e0e0]LOOC[/color] would be to clarify something with a player whom you're roleplaying with, or share something about your status like 'I'm going AFK'
These channels are never to be used to share IC information, and doing so will be struck down swiftly by Admins. Do not mention anything that may hint at events other players would not be aware of in these channels under any circumstances.
[color=#ff6060]Using any information shared in [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] channels, or through methods other than chat in the game, will quickly result in a ban.[/color]

To summarize, when you're in-game:

##DO:
  - Keep in character
  - Act like your character would in the given situation
  - Use [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] channels for help if you need it.

##DON'T:
  - Discuss the round elsewhere (until the round is over)
  - Share information about the round [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color]


## How is Parkstation Specifically for Roleplay?

The intention for Parkstation's roleplay focus is more one of community (That's you!)
We hope to foster a player base interested in slower rounds, more opportunities for character-driven narratives, and an overall more chill outlook on the game in general.
This means Parkstation is intended to be less action-packed, and players will have more expectations to not respond to a situation in the most 'optimal' way, but rather try to find the most 'interesting' resolution.
For instance: Someone has broken into the department you work at, and is currently attempting to steal something dangerous. How should you react?
- Your best chances are grabbing your crowbar and charging them, easily knocking them down, and putting the item away.
- But who would actually do that? The better solution would be to get Security to deal with the situation. Not only is this a more rational response, but it allows Security to do their job and brings other players to interact with your area of the station, including more people in general.

A very important thing to remember in a large-scale roleplaying game such as this one, and one that will often make or break a player is this:
- Sometimes, it's ok to just be a side character in someone else's story.

Someone needs to play the supporting roles, and everyone should be willing to take that mantle now and again. You don't need to be the hero of every story.
This round, you're the bartender who shares the information the investigators need. Next round? Maybe you'll be the crook.

Many of the gameplay choices in Parkstation will mirror this intention, and we hope to see you along for the ride.


## Antagonists

What's an exciting world without someone to make it exciting? Who gets to play the bad guy??
Players often line up to be the criminal- the Zombie, the terrorist, or even just a drug dealer- but if half the people on the station are taking what they want and killing those who oppose them...

You've just ended up with a Random Death Match...

To avoid this, we have the Antag system! The Antag system will select a portioned number of players based on those who have opted in to be the 'bad guys' of the round. The bad guys available are dictated by the game mode, usually selected secretly.
As an antag, it's your job to bring the shock to a round- that DOES NOT mean killing as many people as you can. The goal of an antag should be the same as any other player- tell the most interesting story you can in the round.
Your role is not as simple as pointing a gun, but actually much harder. You don't need to follow the usual rules. You get to break the mold of the average crewman.


## Self-Antag

Self-Antagonizing (self-antag) is when you are NOT an antagonist, yet you go out of your way to break the law, damage the station, or murder.
As described before, if everyone on the station self antags, you end up with RDM. Try to play your role within the world, and remember that being an 'average crewmate' does not simply mean you need to do nothing all round waiting.
Rounds are much more fun when things happen naturally, so maybe try to make friends, have some personal goal, or otherwise build your character as you would any other roleplaying character.
</Document>
