<Document>
# Central Command Takeover Codes

## Code Gamma

[color=#DB7093]Maximum alert level.[/color]

The crew has multiple powerful threats among them, and are all in immediate danger.


[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Head of Security -> Supervisory roles (e.g. Warden) -> Ranking Department Head -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Weapons and Armor[/color] -
Security is required to have multiple lethal weapons on them ready at all times.
Security is required to have a armored hardsuit or strong body armor.

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
Follow due process (Space Law).
Secure and High Security Areas
Heavily guard all High Security Areas.
SECURE THE DISK.

[color=#a4885c]Rules of engagement[/color] -
Security, kill anyone who seems to be a threat (NO, NOT THE CLOWN).
Civilians and Heads, find the safest place you can, keep an emergency weapon or escape.


## Code Delta

[color=#8B0000]Maximum alert level.[/color]

Station self destruct activated or destruction imminent.
Evacuation procedures strongly advised.
All crew and passengers must be evacuated.


[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Ranking Department Head -> Supervisory roles (e.g. Warden) -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Weapons and Armor[/color] -
All personnel are allowed to carry weaponry openly.
Armour heavily advised for all staff.

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
All staff should report to their supervisor for orders.
Summary punishment permitted (Necessary execution).

[color=#a4885c]Secure and High Security Areas[/color] -
Unsecured as needed to facilitate evacuation and retrieval of sensitive materials.

[color=#a4885c]Rules of engagement[/color] -
Lethal force is authorised at the discretion of security personnel or in self defence.

[color=#a4885c]Evacuation[/color] -
Evacuation procedures should be initiated immediately.


## Code Epsilon

[color=#9400D3]True Maximum alert level.[/color]

The station is completely irrecoverable, Central Command will give to chance of escape and neither should the crew.

[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Central Command.
All contracts are terminated.

[color=#a4885c]Weapons and Armor[/color] -
Whatever is required to ensure your own survival.

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
KILL EVERYONE

[color=#a4885c]Secure and High Security Areas[/color] -
Raid all Secure Areas and steal anything you can.

[color=#a4885c]Medical[/color] -
Keep all medicine for yourself, keep yourself alive.

[color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color] -
Lock down your department, try to escape with salvage on their shuttle.
If salvage has no shuttle, build the most secure fortress you can in space outside engineering.

[color=#a4885c]Rules of engagement[/color] -
Kill anyone you see, only you can survive, only you will survive.

[color=#a4885c]Evacuation[/color] -
Evacuation is not a possible option, any shuttle calls will be immediately rejected.
You WILL NOT get any special forces sent to aid the station, good luck.
</Document>
