<Document>
# Standard Operating Procedure

[color=#008000]Note[/color] these are not laws, and the group vote of the heads may alter this as they see fit.
[color=#a4885c]Make sure to read the Alert Procedures.[/color]


## High-Security Areas

What the High-Security Areas are, and who should access them:
- Level one Armory: Non-lethal equipment, any Security personnel.
- Level two Armory: Low-grade lethal weaponry, Security Officers and above.
- Level three Armory: High-grade lethal weaponry, [color=#6494F0]Head of Security[/color] and Warden only.
- Command/Head Offices/AI Satellite: head offices are entirely restricted for entrance without the respective head present. Command may only be entered under the supervision of a head.
- Self Destruct Room/Vault: Bolted at all times, access on request of department head.
- Departments: Unauthorized entrance to a department is trespassing, and may justify a search based on present items.


## Medical Evaluation

Given good medical reason and with documentation, the [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color] may declare any on-duty personnel unfit for duty and remove them from their position. This includes other heads of Staff.

For a medical evaluation to be considered valid, two heads, one of which must be the [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color], must agree that the specified crewmate is unfit for duty.
If they are unfit for duty the [color=#334E6D]Head of Personnel[/color] may demote them to assistant. If demotion is resisted, Security is allowed to detain if necessary.


## Controlled Substances

Any substances that have been restricted or made illegal under Space Law. The current list of controlled substances and any exceptions are as follows:
- Space Drugs
- Chloral Hydrate [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be prescribed by the Psychologist
- Lysergic Acid Diethylamide, (LSD) sometimes referred to as 'MindBreaker'
- Ephedrine [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be in the possession of the [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color] or Security
- DesoxyEphedrine, commonly referred to as 'Meth'
- Any explosive or pyrotechnic compound [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be in a Science department testing area
- Any lethal toxin or toxic substance/compound [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be in the Medical chemistry lab under the supervision of the [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color]
- Any gases that are not normally found in the atmosphere of the station or station's planet [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be possessed by the CE or an Atmospheric Technician
- Liquid Miasma [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be possessed by the [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color] or a Virologist for research purposes only
- XenoBlood
- Corpium
- Any reagents, chemicals, or gasses usually possessed or manufactured by members of a hostile entity

## Controlled Items

Any item that has been restricted or made illegal under Space Law. The current list of controlled items and their exceptions are as follows:
- Any rapid-injection technology, such as chemipens, hyposprays, or autoinjectors, when used offensively or simply containing a potentially lethal or illegal substance [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be in possession of someone authorized by the [color=#52B4E9]CMO[/color]
- Containers or devices used to administer or transport controlled or dangerous substances
- Any cloning technology designed to rapidly grow an adult clone with fully-developed mental faculties [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be contained within the station's Medical department
- Military-grade Explosives [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be possessed by high ranking Security members or another otherwise authorized person
- Automatic Weaponry. This refers to any weapon capable of firing multiple shots when the trigger is depressed once, energy or otherwise [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be possessed by Security, another authorized department of Central Command, or an otherwise authorized entity
- Any other Weaponry [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be possessed by authorized personnel
- Hacking Software or Hardware which allows a person to subvert access to ship systems, bypass access restrictions or attack a vessels computer network
- The corpse of a Xenomorph [color=#a4885c]|[/color] Must be possessed by the [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color] or a Virologist with permission from the [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color] for research purposes only
- Devices, equipment, or tools usually possessed or manufactured by members of a hostile entity


## Research Operations

Science employees are permitted to use their lab spaces as they see fit with the following rules:
- Any human experimentation must be done with the full consent of the test subject, and must not have an undue risk of life. The [color=#6494F0]Head of Security[/color], [color=#52B4E9]Chief Medical Officer[/color], or [color=#D381C9]Research Director[/color] may terminate any human experiment for safety or ethical purposes at their discretion.
- Self-Experimentation is prohibited and is chargeable with endangerment
- Testing of any explosives with a risk of penetrating the hull or causing mass destruction must be done at an off-station site
- Small arms and larger weapons must also be tested at an off-station site if there is a risk to the hull
- Distribution of experimental technology to research personnel for testing is permitted. Permission must be requested from the department head if there are any risks of it being lethal or otherwise dangerous
- Experimental technology may be provided to crew departments for testing and use with the approval of the department head as long as it is not a controlled substance or item
</Document>
