<Document>
# Shadowkin

[color=#008000]Shadowkin are enabled for character creation.[/color]

insert short description here

## Ability Differences

- Need no air to survive.
- Can teleport short distances.
- Can travel to and from The Dark at will.
- Dims nearby lights when in the The Dark.
- Can "speak" in the Empathy chat (~), which only other Shadowkin can understand.
- Slightly less blunt damage.
- A bit more slash damage.
- Slightly more piercing damage.
- Less cold damage.
- Slightly more heat damage.
- Near no cellular damage.
- More bloodloss damage.
- Slightly more shock damage.
- More radiation damage.

## Physical Differences

- Very large and brightly colored eyes with no pupils.
- Very large ears.
- Very fluffy, some humans have given them the nickname "interdimensional floofers".
- Can be Male, Female, or Unisex.
- Can be 18-300 years old and don't appear to age.


# Lore

## Biology

[color=#a88b5e]Physicality[/color]

Shadowkin seem very similar to canine species when looked at.
While mammalian in nature, it is nearly impossible to find any sexual dimorphism between genders, if they even have any.
They seem to all share the same body shape and voices.
The head consists of a snout with nose, sharp teeth in the mouth, and two big ears on top of the head.
In addition to the two big ears, Shadowkin have two more smaller ears lower down, giving them exceptionally good ability to detect where exactly sounds come from.
Shadowkin eyes are usually very large and fully mono-colored; they have no discernable pupils, irises, or similar.
The eye of a Shadowkin is a solid orb of color and, perhaps, the most defining trait.
Throughout all observations, Shadowkin do not seem to age after a certain point.
Some may look older or younger than others, but the aging process seems to stop when the Shadowkin is chronologically in their 20s.
Unusually, compiled medical data on Shadowkin shows that they have no lungs, thus not needing to breathe.

[color=#a88b5e]Mentality[/color]

Shadowkin core personalities is mirrored by their eye color.
Some common colors and their meanings are:

- Red: Determined to reach a goal, even if it means sacrificing others.
- Green: Eager to learn and fit in with others.
- Blue: Very calm and collected, quite shy.

Other colors also exist in addition to these, but are not as common.
The other colors are just mixes of the three main colors.
For example, heres a couple of mixes:

- Purple: Determined, yet less willing to harm, sometimes shy.
- Yellow: Quite eager to be number one, especially via learning.
- Orange: Shy, yet will definitely fight when needed.

There are rumors other colors exist as well.
Other Shadowkin that lose their ability to travel between dimensions have [color=#000000]black eyes[/color] no matter their core personality.
These black-eyed Shadowkin make up the largest number of them living in Realspace.

## History

Shadowkin are creatures native to their so-called Pocket Dimension, a part of space that is unable to be accurately pinpointed and/or visited by most people.
From there, Shadowkin visit our worlds, and sometimes a large number of them are forced into our world and then live among us.
What exactly causes these mass migrations is unknown, but may have relation to them losing their ability to travel between dimensions.

[color=#a88b5e]Homeworld[/color]

While no home system or world has been found, some Shadowkin talk about dreaming of their homeworld, describing a lush and green land with abundant resources.

[color=#a88b5e]Racial/Government Status[/color]

There currently exists no Shadowkin government, and with Shadowkin being as rare as they are, they tend to fit into currently established societies and civilisations,  with varying degress of success in the past.
In recent years, however, many cultures have taken to accepting Shadowkin as another galactic constant, going as far as allowing them lives similar to those that any of the other species would lead.

Some systems early on took and experimented on Shadowkin, in an attempt to utilise their powers in various technology, and even recreating them with very experimental technology.
The tests failed and this was met with a lot of resistance from Shadowkin, many of them being killed or becoming blackeyes in the process.
After this, those systems realised that Shadowkin were a sentient species, and deeply apologised for their actions.

## Culture

[color=#a88b5e]The Typical Experience[/color]

Most times, life is pretty normal. A Shadowkin can have a job, go to the job to work, then spend time off with friends.
The fact is most times of the day, the small abilities one might have are nice, but not overly useful. Sure, a Shadowkin could dim the nearby lights, but at the same time, the Shadekin could also just flick the lightswitch.
However, it can sometimes happen that when a Shadowkin slept in and needs to get to work quickly, they might just teleport to work.
Some people might be overly wary of you, some might be drawn towards you.
Many Shadowkin are used to not wearing clothes, which can lead to some awkward situations, but those are generally the same situations any other furred species would have.

[color=#a88b5e]Language[/color]

The only recorded spoken language of the Shadowkin is an unusual language named "Mar", named after the fact that every single word in this language is the word "mar".
Spoken in different tones, with more or less emphasis on the various parts, or by drawing out parts of this word, a multitiude of different "mar"s can be created, but they follow no apparent conventions.
Shadowkin can perfectly understand each other though and discuss complex topics using only this one word.
The Shadowkin can hear the Mar language from anywhere and understand it via Empathy, yet do not know who it is from unless they are close enough to see the sender.
Other humanoid species are incapable of understanding or learning Mar, as they are unable to accentuate their speech in the same way or hear some of the silent, Empathic tones they use.
Shadowkin tend to learn one or more languages of the Realspace beings.
The capability in such learned languages depends fully on each single Shadowkin, where some have only very broken capabilities, while others are fluent in several languages.

[color=#a88b5e]Naming Conventions[/color]

Shadowkin tend to name themselves with a singular word, ranging from states of being, such as Lone and Collected, to words that describe their memories connected to their supposed homeworld, like Dreamer.
Name schemes of the humans are usually frowned upon, as they do not reflect upon the Shadowkin, resulting in reactions ranging anywhere from an actual frown to being entirely ignored.
Shadowkin following another species naming scheme are often blackeyes, not fitting in with other Shadowkin as well.
Names hold a great deal for Shadowkin because of how closely they are often tied to describing who they are.
Following life changing events, Shadowkin often change their names to reflect the new person they have become.

[color=#a88b5e]Rumors and Speculation[/color]

Shadowkin are beings from another dimension, capable of performing feats other could only describe as "magic", with no scientific explanation.
It is speculated that Shadowkin actually have a whole nation in their own dimension, and those that come to Realspace simply collectively refuse to talk about it.
Sometimes Shadowkin mention a "Hub", acting as evidence for this theory.
Some believe Shadowkin are the result of experimentation, though them being taken and experimented on is a large piece of evidence denying this theory.
Some believe Shadowkin are the result of an expedition crew that disappeared hundreds of years ago, even though the first Shadowkin sightings were long before that.
Obviously, this expedition ship performed time travel.

## OOC Notes

[color=#FF0000]"Secret" Shadowkin Knowledge[/color]
[color=#FF0000]([/color]Act as if you do not know this in RP unless you are a Shadowkin[color=#FF0000])[/color]
[color=#FF0000]([/color]Maybe even avoid reading this and learn the secret knowledge in-round[color=#FF0000])[/color]

[color=#a88b5e]History[/color]

Shadowkin used to live on a very lush forest planet, using primitive technology to work with metal, create tools, and build stone structures.
According to the dreams, Shadowkin back then had forged tools and blades, but had no electricity, presumably putting them at a medieval technology level.
In a sudden event, everyone and everything organic suddenly found themselves in an alternate dimension, sucked straight out of their previous home.
The Shadowkin being ripped from their homes happened in three total "dimensional ripples".
Now stuck in this alternate dimension, Shadowkin changed a lot.
They stopped aging and with time developed the ability to use the energy of this dimension to power their unusual "magic".
And even later, they learned how to leave the dimension and travel to realspace and back again.
However, as the eons passes, memories became shady of their home.
Many Shadowkin forgot more and more about their thousands of years that they had lived, reducing memory to focus on the more important closer time.
However in dreams, Shadowkin, even those born in Realspace, often have visions of their home planet.
And some dreams trigger events, like meeting someone they knew from the past, can cause flashes of memory to appear.
As such, it can happen that two Shadowkin can randomly meet and remember that they have met hundreds of years ago, often confusing nearby unknowing humanoids.

[color=#a88b5e]Biology[/color]

If a shadowkin personality changes drastically, their eye color will change as an effect, reflecting upon their new personality.
Shadowkin, being ageless entities, can look older or younger, but that is merely a visual representation of how they feel about their own age.
22 years after birth a Shadowkin stops aging, and in all of their history no instance of them dying of old age has been recorded.

[color=#a88b5e]The Ritual[/color]

When a Shadowkin reaches adulthood, they undergo a "Ritual".
During this Ritual they intentionally overload their energy reserves, forcing their capacity to expand rapidly in order to gain enough energy to travel between dimensions.
Most Shadowkin pass the Ritual and thats the end of it, but some Shadowkin perish or become blackeyes during the ritual.

[color=#a88b5e]Important Terminology[/color]

[color=#a88b5e]Shadowkin:[/color]
The name given for your race.
While your race doesn't have a name for itself, this is how most of the Galaxy refers to you.

[color=#a88b5e]The Dark:[/color]
The other dimension where you are from.
There are theories that The Dark and Bluespace are connected, but you don't know the details about that.
The Dark is a dimension where strange rules apply.
For outsiders who somehow enter it, whatever they imagine to be in there, they see there, if not too complex.
If an outsider comes with a willing Shadowkin they may see what the Shadowkin sees, being anything they imagine, or a reflection of the station.

[color=#a88b5e]Blackeyes:[/color]
A Shadowkin who has undergone and failed the Ritual, or lost their ability via other methods.
The blackeyes, obviously, have completely black eyes, no matter their actual personality.
They choose a new name, of which follows a favorite species' naming scheme.
They are often ignored or left alone more by other Shadowkin.

[color=#a88b5e]Mar:[/color]
A word used to verbally communicate feelinds, emotions, wishes, hopes, ideas, and whatever, in addition to your Empathy.

</Document>
