<Document>
# Common Alert Levels

## Code Green

[color=#008000]Standard operating procedure.[/color]

There is no known threat to the ship or crew.


[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Ranking Department Head -> Supervisory roles -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Weapons and Armor[/color] -
Security Officers are authorized to be equipped with low-grade lethal weapons.

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
Follow due process (Space Law).

[color=#a4885c]Medical[/color] -
Binary suit sensor setting at a minimum is recommended.

[color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color] -
EVA suit wear is only advised for proper EVA use.

[color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color] -
Engage with the minimum required force to subdue a target, dependent on their threat and level of compliance.
De-escalation prioritized.


## Code Blue

[color=#1E90FF]Elevated alert level.[/color]

Unknown, suspected, or low-grade security threat to vessel or crew.


[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Head of Security -> Ranking Department Head -> Supervisory roles -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Weapons and Armor[/color] -
Lethal weapons may be openly carried by Security Officers.
Helmets are recommended for security personnel.

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
Security personnel are required to report to their supervisor for orders.
Arrests and searches may be performed at the discretion of security personnel, but following Space Law procedure is required for Brigging.

[color=#a4885c]Medical[/color] -
Binary suit sensor setting at a minimum is highly recommended.
EVA suit wear is recommended for emergency response technicians.

[color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color] -
EVA suit wear is suggested for engineers.
Emergency internals should be easily accessible for all personnel.

[color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color] -
Engage with the minimum required force to subdue a target, dependent on their threat and level of compliance.



## Code Red

[color=#FF0000]Emergency alert level.[/color]

There is a known or multiple known urgent threats on the station.

[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Head of Security -> Department/available Head -> Supervisory roles -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Weapons and Armor[/color] -
Open carry of weapons is permitted for all authorized personnel.
Body armor, helmets, and weapon are heavily advised for security.
It is recommended to staff an Officer or Peacekeeper at potential danger sites.

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
Arrests and searches may be performed at the discretion of security personnel.
All personnel, including security staff, should obey relevant instructions from emergency services attending their emergency situations. Temporary Brig times are authorized until the threat is handled.

[color=#a4885c]Medical[/color] -
Coordinate suit sensors are heavily advised.
EVA suit wear is heavily advised for emergency responders.

[color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color] -
EVA suit wear is advised for all engineers.
Emergency internals are heavily advised for all personnel.

[color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color] -
Engage with the minimum required force to subdue a target, dependent on their threat and level of compliance, as security staff.
</Document>
