<Document>
# Specific Alert Levels

## Code Violet

[color=#EE82EE]Elevated alert level.[/color]

There is a serious viral outbreak, many personnel are injured, or (will be) dead, or another major medical emergency.


[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Chief medical officer -> Ranking Department Head -> Supervisory roles -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
Follow due process (Space Law).
Non-medical personnel should ensure they aren't getting in any medical staff's way, and should obey relevant instructions from medical personnel, such as leaving an area, remaining in quarantine, or assisting in rescue efforts if capable.

[color=#a4885c]Medical[/color] -
Medical personnel should report to their supervisor for orders.
EVA equipment is recommended for emergency responders, if relevant.
Suit Sensors are advised to be set to the highest possible level.
All personnel should ensure they have a functioning emergency air supply.


## Code Yellow

[color=#FFFF00]Elevated alert level.[/color]

The ship has suffered severe damage, the power source can't function, the singularity is loose, there is a major fire, an incoming meteor storm, or another major engineering emergency.


[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Chief engineer -> Ranking Department Head -> Supervisory roles -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
Follow due process (Space Law).
Non-engineering personnel are advised to evacuate any affected areas and should obey relevant instructions from engineering personnel, such as an order to evacuate or stay in an area.

[color=#a4885c]Medical[/color] -
EVA equipment is recommended for emergency responders.
Suit Sensors are advised to be set to the highest possible level.
All personnel should ensure they have a functioning emergency air supply.

[color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color] -
Engineering personnel should report to their supervisor for orders.
EVA suits are recommended.

[color=#a4885c]Evacuation[/color] -
The ship should be evacuated if the damage is not feasibly repairable without great loss of life, if not evacuating would result in total loss of crew, or if the damage is so severe that breakup is imminent.


## Code White

[color=#F6CCF6]Elevated alert level.[/color]

There is a major psionic emergency.

[color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color] -
Centcom -> Group vote among Heads -> Mystagogue -> Ranking Department Head -> Supervisory roles -> Standard Crew

[color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color] -
Follow due process (Space Law).
ROE on mindbreaker is lifted.
Try to avoid the use of lethal force.
Wear psionic insulation if possible.

[color=#a4885c]Secure and High Security Areas[/color] -
It is recommended to have a group of two people guard the inside of High-Security Areas
In the case of a mindswapper, having a second guard will allow easier apprehension of the swapper.
In the case of a mass sleep user, make sure the guards are several (~10) meters away from each other at least.

[color=#a4885c]Medical[/color] -
Suit Sensors are recommended to be set to the highest possible level.
Prepare psionic insulation for anyone who wants it.
Prepare for an increase in burn and brain damage.

[color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color] -
Engineering personnel should report to their supervisor for orders.
EVA suits are recommended, but not fully equipped for easy indentification.
Help with disposing of glimmer probers may be required.

[color=#a4885c]Epistemics[/color] -
Shut off glimmer probers if possible.
Get assistance from security and engineering to destroy probers if needed.

[color=#a4885c]Evacuation[/color] -
The ship should be evacuated only if the glimmer spiral seems irrecoverable even after all probers are destroyed and multiple psionics are golemized.
Another case for evacuation would be if too many psionic signatures have manifested, and are too powerful to dispel.
</Document>
